Finding Aid for Henry Carter Adams Papers, 1864-1924
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Addresses, Lectures and Writings
  - Writings
    - Collected essays and addresses, 1 volumes (Box 27)
      (published articles)
- Miscellaneous
  The Miscellaneous series includes smaller files relating to the U-M Department of Economics, some student research papers, biographical information, scrapbooks, newspaper clippings, and some letters and other materials of Mrs. Henry Carter Adams.
  - U-M Department of Economics materials (Box 27)
  - U-M student term papers (Box 27)
  - Personal and bibliographical materials, 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Articles and papers about Henry Carter Adams (Box 27)
  - Scrapbooks, 2 volumes (Box 28)
  - Newspaper clippings, 7 folders (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous, 4 folders (Box 28)
  - Papers of Mrs. Henry Carter Adams, 1917-1934; 5 folders (Box 28)
- Topical File, 1908-1911
  The Topical File series was received several years after the major accession of Adams papers. It covers the years 1908 to 1911, is arranged alphabetically, and relates primarily to railroad and utility rates and statistical issues.
  - Committee on Uniform Railway Statistics, 4 folders (Box 29)
  - Accounting Officers Association (Box 29)
  - Additions and betterments (Box 29)
  - Advance rate hearings (Box 29)
  - Ann Arbor Office (Box 29)
  - Annual reports (Box 29)
  - Balance sheet correspondence (Box 29)
  - Board of examiners (Box 29)
  - Capitalization (Box 29)
  - Corporation tax file (Box 29)
  - Denver and Rio Grande Railroad (Box 29)
  - Depreciation of maintenance of way and structures (Box 29)
  - Destruction of records (Box 29)
  - Division of Statistics and Accounts (Box 29)
  - Duluth, South Shore and Atlantic Railroad (Box 29)
  - Electric railways (Box 29)
  - Employees, reclassification of (Box 29)
  - Express companies, 2 folders (Box 29)
  - General (Box 29)
  - G Street building (Box 29)
  - Income account (Box 29)
  - Industrial Railroad Division (Box 29)
  - Joint facilities file (Box 29)
  - Jurisdiction (Box 29)
  - Missouri Pacific Railroad (Box 30)
  - New York City Subways (Box 30)
  - Outside operations (Box 30)
  - Pass accounts (Box 30)
  - Pipe lines (Box 30)
  - Property abandoned (Box 30)
  - Pullman matters, 4 folders (Box 30)
  - Railroad Securities Commission (Box 30)
  - Telegraph Company (Box 30)
  - Telegraph literature (Box 30)
  - Telephone company (Box 30)
  - Texas Railroad Commission (Box 30)
  - Undercharges, collection of (Box 30)
  - Union Pacific report (Box 30)
  - Validating Bureau (Box 30)
  - Valuation (Box 30)
  - Water carriers (Box 30)
  - Western Pacific Railroad (Box 30)
  - Synopses of certain examiners reports (Box 30)
  - Texts of the ICC law (Box 30)
  - Miscellanea (Box 30)
- Photographs
  (see also Uam oversize folder)
  Photographs includes portraits of Adams and other family members and views of his home on Hill Street in Ann Arbor, Michigan.
  - Henry Carter Adams
    - Portraits (Box 31)
    - Homes, Miscellaneous (Box 31)
    - House, 1421 Hill Street, Ann Arbor
      - Exterior (Box 31)
      - Interior (Box 31)
      - Gardens (Box 31)
  - Bertha Wright Adams (HCA wife) (Box 31)
  - Henry C. Adams (HCA son) (Box 31)
  - Theodore Adams (HCA son) (Box 31)
  - Thomas Adams (HCA son)
    - Portraits (Box 31)
    - European trip, 1914, pre-August (Box 31)
  - Elizabeth Adams (HCA mother) (Box 31)
  - Adams family, various (Box 31)
Partial Index to Correspondence
Adams, Bertha H. Wright.
Correspondence throughout collection after 1889.
Adams, Charles Kendall, 1835-1902.
May 30, 1882; Feb. 12, 1883; Jan. 31, 1884; Feb. 9, 1884; Mar. 7, 1884; Mar. 9, 1884; Apr. 9, 1884; Apr. 25, 1884; May 12, 1884; May 17, 1884; May 26, 1884; Mar. 11, 1885; May 18, 1885; Apr. 21, 1890; Jan. 24, 1895; Feb. 4, 1895; Mar. 5, 1897; Feb. 4, 1899; Feb. 23, 1899.
Adams, Elizabeth Sylvia Ann (Douglass), 1821-1905.
Correspondence throughout collection.
Adams, Ephraim, 1818-1907.
Correspondence throughout collection.
Adams, Ephraim Douglass, 1865-1930.
Correspondence throughout collection.
Adams, Herbert Baxter, 1850-1901.
May 12, 1882; June 15, 1882; Oct. 17, 1883; Jan. 24, 1884; Feb. 20, 1884; Mar. 18, 1884; Apr. 27, 1884; May 6, 1884; June 25, 1884; Aug. 23, 1884; Mar. 12, 1885; May 21, 1890; Jan. 18, 1895; Feb. 18, 1895; May 13, 1895; Feb. 5, 1896; Feb. 11, 1896; Mar. 25, 1896, Jan. 30, 1901
Addams, Jane, 1860-1935.
June 28, 1895, Sept. 11, 1899, Mar. 6, 1901.
Allison, William B. (William Boyd), 1829-1908.
Jan. 21, 1888.
Anderson, William J.
March 23, 1900
Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.
Aug. 1, 1899 and 1899 undated and correspondence throughout collection.
Ashley, H. W.
Dec. 8, Dec. 26, 1900
Baker, Ray Stannard, 1870-1946.
Jan. 2, 1906.
Bartlett, Hamilton M.
Correspondence throughout collection.
Beakes, Samuel Willard, 1861-1927.
June 8, 1914.
Bemis, Edward Webster, 1860-1930.
May 3, 1895; May 23, 1895; Dec. 17, 1896; Dec. 28, 1896; Dec. 10, 1897; May 11, 1899; May 16, 1899; Mar. 22, 1901; Apr. 9, 1901; Apr. 23, 1901; May 18, 1901; May 27, 1901; Dec. 18, 1905; Feb. 28, 1906; Mar. 8, 1906.
Brandeis, Louis Dembitz, 1856-1941.
June 14, 1911.
Brown, W. C. (William Carlos), 1853-1924.
Nov. 5, 1910; May 2, 1911; June 26, 1911; Oct. 10, 1911; Nov. 7, 1911.
Bullock, Charles Jesse, 1869-1941.
Apr. 7, 1902; Apr. 16, 1902; Oct. 24, 1902; Oct. 19, 1905; Mar. 2, 1915; Mar. 29, 1915; Apr. 26, 1915; May 24, 1915; Aug. 15, 1916; May 28, 1918; June 21, 1918.
Burton, Marion LeRoy, 1874-1925.
Sept. 21, 1920.
Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947.
Jan. 11, 1902.
Butterfield, Kenyon L. (Kenyon Leech), 1868-1935.
Jan. 16, Feb. 6, Mar. 5, May 29, Nov. 17, 1900
Campbell, Milo D.
May 15, 1900
Canfield, James Hulme, 1847-1909.
May 20, 1895; May 27, 1895; June 11, 1895.
Clark, Frederick Converse
April 30, May 25, 1900
Clark, John Bates, 1847-1938.
Dec. 10, 1886; Dec. 29, 1886; Feb. 17, 1887; May 31, 1887; May 21, 1889; Sept. 18, 1890; Jan. 10, 1895; 1895; Jan. 4, 1896; June 3, 1896; July 10, 1901; July 26, 1901; Mar. 12, 1904; Dec. 12, 1919.
Clements, William L. (William Lawrence), 1861-1934.
Oct. 30, 1916.
Commons, John Rogers, 1862-1945.
Jan. 9, 1895; Mar. 11, 1895; Apr. 6, 1895; Oct. 3, 1902; Jan. 2, 1903; Jan. 26, 1903; Apr. 21, 1915, undated.
Conant, Charles A. (Charles Arthur), 1861-1915.
Aug. 27, Oct. 24, Nov. 9, 1900
Cooley, Charles Horton, 1864-1929.
May 7, 1889; June 8, 1889; May 15, 1890; May 19, 1896; Oct. 18, 1899; Dec. 4, 1920.
Cooley, Lyman Edgar, 1850-1917.
Oct. 13, 1899
Cooley, Mortimer E. (Mortimer Elwyn), 1855-1944.
Sept. 16, 1887; Nov. 22, 1900; Sept. 29, 1902; Jan. 25, 1906; Jan. 30, 1907; July 11, 1907; Mar. 15, 1915; Apr. 7, 1915; July 12, 1915; July 30, 1919.
Cooley, Thomas McIntyre, 1824-1898.
Aug. 13, 1888; Aug. 21, 1888; Oct. 5, 1888; Oct. 12, 1888; Nov. 3, 1888; Jan. 19, 1889; Feb. 18, 1889; Mar. 18, 1889.
Dawson, William Mercer Owens, 1853-1916.
Mar. 21, 1906; Apr. 30, 1906; May 18, 1906.
Dewey, Davis Rich, 1858-1942.
Nov. 24, 1896; Oct. 4, 1898; Jan. 21, 1899; Jan. 31, 1901; Jan. 24, 1902; Feb. 12, 1903; Apr. 28, 1904.
Dewey, John 1859-1952.
Apr. 29, 1889; Jan. 23, 1899; Feb. 1, 1899; Mar. 8, 1899.
Dixon, Frank Haigh, 1869-.
Correspondence throughout collection beginning 1895, and undated.
D'Ooge, Martin Luther, 1839-1915.
Nov. 8, 1888.
Durand, Edward Dana, b. 1871.
Dec. 8, 1900, Dec. 17, 1900
Effinger, John Robert, 1869-1933.
August 24, 1899
Elkins, Stephen B. (Stephen Benton), 1841-1911.
July 17, 1909.
Ely, Richard Theodore, 1854-1943.
Correspondence throughout collection.
Ely, Richard Theodore, 1854-1943.
Jan. 29, May 1, June 11, June 16, Oct. 10, Nov. 19, 1900
Evans, Elizabeth G.
Aug. 30, Nov. 22, 1900
Fairchild, Fred Rogers, 1877-1966.
June 8, 1918; June 24, 1918.
Fetter, Frank A. (Frank Albert), 1863-1949.
Jan. 21, 1902; Nov. 8, 1902; Nov. 14, 1903; June 11, 1904.
Fisher, Irving, 1867-1947.
Oct. 16, 1914; Oct. 5, 1918.
Friday, David, 1876-1945.
Feb. 26, May 6, 1919
Fuertes, E.A.
Feb. 12, 1900
Giddings, Franklin Henry, 1855-1931.
Mar. 3, 1896; Oct. 2, 1896; Oct. 7, 1896.
Gifford, Walter Sherman, 1885-
Apr. 26, 1920.
Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1831-1908.
Jan. 18, 1881; Jan. 8, 1887; Apr. 27, 1889; Jan. 13, 1896.
Gore, Mr. (Thomas Pryor), 1870-1949.
July, 1912.
Gray, John Henry, 1859-
Jan. 29, 1901
Guthe, Karl Eugen, 1866-1915.
Oct. 22, 1912; Dec. 6, 1912.
Hadley, Arthur Twining, 1856-1930.
Sept. 18, 1885; Sept. 26, 1885; Oct. 19, 1885; May 1, 1886; Nov. 21, 1886; Sept. 10, 1887; May 27, 1899.
Hanshue, J.J.
Sept. 4, 1899
Hart, Albert Bushnell, 1854-1943.
Aug. 3, 1895; Aug. 11, 1895; Nov. 10, 1895.
Hathaway, F.R.
May 2, 1900
Hawes, Harry B.
Feb. 15, 1900
Hawley, Willis Chatman
March 6, 1900, March 17, 1900
Hill, Robert Thomas, 1858-1941.
June 1, 1900
Hollander, Jacob Harry, 1871-1940.
May 22, 1900, and correspondence throughout collection.
Hopkins, Albert J. (Albert Jarvis), 1846-1922.
Jan. 7, 1902.
Hull, Charles Henry, 1864-
Sept. 19, 1886; Feb. 26, 1895; Apr. 20, 1895; Aug. 1, 1896; Jan. 3, 1899; Mar. 1, 1899; June 17, 1899; Oct. 1899, Dec. 1899, Jan. 9, 18, 27 1900, Feb. 10, 14, 1900, April 16, 1900, May 10, 1900, Nov. 7, 1900; Apr. 26, 1901; Apr. 1, 1902; Apr. 16, 1902; Apr. 18, 1902; Apr. 24, 1902.
Hutchins, Harry B. (Harry Burns), 1847-1930.
Jan. 31, 1898; Apr. 28, 1898; Oct. 27, 1899; June 3, 1916; June 5, 1916; Oct. 17, 1919.
James, Edmund J. (Edmund Janes), 1855-1925.
Jan. 8, 1884; Sept. 17, 1884; Mar. 24, 1885; July 29, 1895; Nov. 3, 1900; Nov. 20, 1901; July 8, 1905.
Jameson, J. (John Franklin), 1859-1937.
June 19, 1885.
Jeffery, Edward Turner, 1843-1927.
Nov. 13, 1900
Jenks, Jeremiah Whipple, 1856-1929.
Correspondence throughout collection.
Johnson, Emory R. (Emory Richard), 1864-1950.
Aug. 7, 1899, Sept. 18, 1899, Sept. 30, 1899, Dec. 11, 1899, Oct. 30, 1899
Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931.
May 6, 1885; Mar. 23, 1889; Mar. 27, 1889; Aug. 4, 1891; Aug. 24, 1891; Jan. 28, 1899; Apr. 15, 1904.
Jruks, J. W.
April 3, 1900
Knight, George W. (George Wells), 1858-1932.
May 17, 1885; May 10, 1889; May 16, 1889; May 20, 1889; May 24, 1889; Jan. 8, 1895; Feb. 19, 1895.
Labadie, Jo, 1850-1933.
August 21, 1899
Lathrop, Julia Clifford, 1858-1932.
March 7, 1899
Laughlin, J. Laurence (James Laurence), 1850-1933.
Mar. 3, 1883; Oct. 17, 1885; Jan. 4, 1895; Jan. 8, 1901; Jan. 23, 1901; Feb. 12, 1902; Feb. 28, 1902; May 2, 1903; Jan. 8, 1906; Oct. 21, 1914; Oct. 23, 1914; Apr. 7, 1915; July 16, 1920; Aug. 24, 1920; Aug. 31, 1920; Oct. 16, 1920; Mar. 5, 1921.
Lawton, Charles De Witt, 1835-1909.
Jan. 20, 27, 1900
Lewis, David J. (David John), 1869-1952.
Jan. 6, 1913.
Manny, Frank Addison, 1868-1954.
May 4, 1895.
Martin, H. B.
August 2, 1899
Mayo-Smith, Richmond, 1854-1901.
June 3, 1896; Nov. 24, 1898; Dec. 13, 1898; Jan. 18, 1900
Mead, Edwin Doak, 1849-1937.
Jan. 31, 1899; May 17, 1899; Sept. 15, 1899; Nov. 18, 1899; Nov. 29, 1899; Sept. 3, 1903.
Newcomb, H. T. (Harry Turner), 1867-1944.
Oct. 20, Dec. 31, 1900
Ono, Yeijiro
August 29, 1899, Mar. 4, 1899, April 23, 1900, June 1, 1900
Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.
Feb. 14, 1901; Apr. 22, 1911.
Page, Walter Hines, 1855-1918.
Feb. 4, 1895; Feb. 26, 1895; Mar. 20, 1897; Mar. 31, 1897; Apr. 20, 1897; May 4, 1897; June 16, 1897; Jan. 14, 1898; Apr. 2, 1898; Nov. 26, 1898; Jan. 2, 1899; Mar. 24, 1899.
Paxson, Frederic L. (Frederic Logan), 1877-1948.
Jan. 29, 1915.
Peabody, Charles
September 26, 1899
Pickard, Josiah Little, 1824-1914.
Feb. 4, 1882; Nov. 11, 1882.
Raymond, J. Everett
Feb. 20, 1900
Ripley, William Zebina, 1867-1941.
Feb. 21, 1900, Mar. 5, 1900, Oct. 27, 1900, Dec. 31, 1900; Mar. 8, 1901; Feb. 21, 1902; Mar. 29, 1902; Oct. 10, 1902; June 1, 1903; Sept. 8, 1904; Mar. 30, 1915; Apr. 9, 1915; May 10, 1921.
Rogers, Henry Wade, 1853-1926.
Aug. 25, 1891; Aug. 31, 1891; Sept. 5, 1891; Sept. 11, 1891; Feb. 6, 1899.
Rosenthal, Lessing, 1868-1949.
Jan. 26, 1900
Salter, William Mackintire, 1853-1931.
Sept. 24, 1981; Nov. 20, 1981; July 18, 1982; August 8, 1982; Sept. 27, 1982; Oct. 6, 1982; Oct. 24, 1982; Nov. 10, 1982; May 25, 1983; June 17, 1983; Oct. 1, 1984; Dec. 30, 1984; June 25, 1985; April 6, 1986; Sept. 9, 1990; Aug. 7, 1995; Aug. 11, 1995; Aug. 18, 1995; Aug. 10, 1996; Aug. 28, 1996; Feb. 5, 1907; April 24, 1907; April 30, 1907.
Sanborn, F. B. (Franklin Benjamin), 1831-1917.
Dec. 3, 1884.
Sedgwick, W. T. (William Thompson), 1855-1921.
Oct. 27, 1881.
Seligman, Edwin Robert Anderson, 1861-1939.
Nov. 12, 1899, Jan. 4, 1900, Jan. 25, 1900, Feb. 4, 1900, Mar. 28, 1900, Apr. 29, 1900, May 18, 1900; Correspondence throughout collection.
Sharfman, Isaiah Leo, 1886-
Dec. 18, 1920; Correspondence throughout collection.
Shaw, Albert, 1857-1947.
May 28, 1883; June 12, 1883; June 5, 1885; June 17, 1885; Apr. 23, 1886; Nov. 19, 1889; Jan. 5, 1895; Aug. 6, 1895; Dec. 3, 1896; Dec. 9, 1896; Sept. 6, 1898; Dec. 1, 1898; Jan. 4, 1899; Feb. 2, 1899; Apr. 2, 1904.
Shibley, George H. (George Henry), b. 1861.
March 25, 1900
Small, Albion Woodbury, 1859-1926.
July 29, 1895; Feb. 24, 1899; Nov. 16, 1899; Dec. 17, 1903; Dec. 24, 1903; Mar. 5, 1904; Mar. 9, 1904; Mar. 17, 1904; June 15, 1904; June 28, 1904; July 15, 1904.
Smith, Henry Cassorte, 1859-1911.
Mar. 28, 1901, Mar. 30, 1901.
Smith, J. Allen (James Allen), 1860-1926.
July 29, 1895; Aug. 5, 1895; Aug. 12, 1895; Aug. 13, 1895; Aug. 17, 1895; Sept. 23, 1895; Oct. 31, 1895; Dec. 23, 1895; Feb. 7, 1896; Mar. 16, 1896; Apr. 25, 1896; June 27, 1896; June 15, 1897; Dec. 2, 1898; Jan. 4, 1899; Jan. 5, 1899; Apr. 18, 1899; Jan. 14, 1901; Aug. 9, 1906.
Smith, John McMunn C., 1853-1923.
July 14, 1917.
Stanley, Augustus Owsley, 1867-1958.
June 10, 1911; July 4, 1911.
Stearns, Justus S. (Justus Smith), b. 1845.
Aug. 22, 1899
Stephens, E. W.
Oct. 20, 1900
Taussig, Frank William, 1859-1940.
Correspondence throughout collection.
Taylor, Graham, 1851-1938.
Oct. 14, 1896; Nov. 16, 1896; June 27, 1897; Feb. 27, 1899; Mar. 23, 1899; June 10, 1899; Feb. 15, 1900; Jan. 21, 1901; Apr. 2, 1901; Oct. 18, 1902; Sept. 14, 1905.
Thomas, Calvin, 1854-1919.
Oct. 16, 1900, Nov. 5, 1900
Thomas, Calvin, 1854-1919.
Mar. 15, 1882; Apr. 14, 1883; Feb. 24, 1884; Mar. 5, 1884; May 10, 1885; May 9, 1886; Dec. 6, 1896; June 5, 1901.
Towne, Charles Arnette, 1858-1928.
Jan. 11, 1901.
Townsend, Charles E. (Charles Elroy), 1856-1924.
Dec. 14, 1904; Feb. 10, 1905; Apr. 20, 1905; Apr. 1, 1920.
Tunell, George Gerard.
Oct. 30, 1899, Nov. 3, 1899, Dec. 1, 1899
Tyler, Moses Coit, 1835-1900.
Feb. 20, 1890; Feb. 22, 1890.
Van Hise, Charles Richard, 1857-1918.
Mar. 17, 1904.
Vaughan, Victor C. (Victor Clarence), 1851-1929.
Oct. 9, 1897; Oct. 16, 1897; Nov. 25, 1897.
Veblen, Thorstein, 1857-1929.
Oct. 19, 1899
Ward, Lester Frank, 1841-1913.
Feb. 26, 1899.
Wells, David Ames, 1828-1898.
Feb. 22, 1884; Mar. 1, 1884; Mar. 19, 1884; Mar. 23, 1884.
Wheeler, Benjamin Ide, 1854-1927.
Dec. 7, 1903; Sept. 27, 1904; Oct. 11, 1904.
White, Andrew Dickson, 1832-1918.
May 12, 1881; Apr. 6, 1882; Nov. 10, 1882; June 23, 1883; Apr. 29, 1887; July 11, 1887; June 18, 1896.
Wilcox, Delos F. (Delos Franklin), 1878-1928.
Mar. 27, 1897; June 23, 1906; May 3, 1919, May 20, 1919
Wilcox, Walter Francis, 1861-
Nov. 1, 1899; correspondence throughout collection.
Williams, John Sharp, 1854-1932.
Apr. 24, 1895.
Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924.
Feb. 26, 1890.